alainak@u.northwestern.edu alainakafkes.github.io 708.476.8695

Alaina Kafkes

Technical Skills

Proficient

C++, Python, Javascript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Sass, Swift

Developing

Riot.js, Gulp, Java, Go, SQL, C, Angular.js

Awards

PanHellenic Scholar

May 2016

Honors outstanding college students of Hellenic descent.

Dean's List

December 2013 - Present

Granted to those with a quarter GPA greater than 3.70. Five-time recipient.

Personal Projects

Dibz

January 2016 – Present

Founded and developed a web app that offers online sellers the ability to generate a bitlink for a listing to share in informal communities. Launching to 50+ beta testers. Worked extensively with Javascript, Riot.js, Firebase API.

Rude

February 2016 (HackIllinois)

Coded Android app that encourages users to spend quality time socializing without checking their phone. Worked extensively with Java, Facebook API.

May 2016 - Present

Developing Rude as an iPhone app. Worked extensively with Swift.

Education

Northwestern University | Computer Science, minor in Chemistry

Anticipated June 2017

Cumulative GPA: 3.76/4.00 | Major GPA: 4.00/4.00

Work Experience

GE Healthcare | Software Engineering Intern

Anticipated June 2016

Health Aware Bits Lab | Software Engineer

January 2016 - March 2016

Constructed "Myrror" from a proximity sensor, two-way mirror, and monitor, then built corresponding web app to improve young adults' body confidence. Technologies used: C++, HTML, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Firebase API.

Northwestern University | Teaching Assistant

December 2015 - Present

Assists students in introductory programming course through the creation of a network and with object-oriented programming questions. Languages used: C++.

National Science Foundation | REU Intern

June 2015 - August 2015

Coded scripts to supplement density functional theory (DFT) calculations.

Computationally modeled and optimized aluminum biomolecule structures.

Languages used: Puthon.

Extracurriculars & Offices Held

Women in Computing | Internal President

April 2015 – Present

Established and chairs first-ever mentorship program for undergraduate and graduate women in tech, with over 40 participants in the pilot program. Cosponsors, coordinates and teaches at campus-wide weekly hack nights.

EPIC | Project Lead & Software Engineer

April 2016 - Present

Built website for the Northwestern Venture Challenge. Technologies used: Sass, Gulp, Javascript, HTML, CSS.

Peer Health Exchange | Senior Health Educator

September 2014 - Present

Teaches the ninth grade health curriculum at Chicago Public Schools.